<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Arturo Torres</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Arturo Torres</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Urban landscape artificialization leads to increased flood hazards in the most vulnerable locations (Under review)</title>
      <link>/publication/p20230426_scs_floods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/p20230426_scs_floods/</guid>
      <description>Rainfall data assimilation for urban flood modelling     Rainfall data assimilation in flood modelling was used to improve the accuracy of rainfall inputs for flood prediction. It involves integrating observed rainfall data from various sources, such as weather stations, radar systems, or satellite measurements, into a hydrological model. By assimilating the observed rainfall data, the model can adjust and update its initial rainfall estimates, resulting in more reliable and precise flood predictions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calibration for an Ensemble of Grapevine Phenology Models under Different Optimization Algorithms</title>
      <link>/publication/p20230226_agronomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/p20230226_agronomy/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     Vine phenology modelling is increasingly important for winegrowers and viticulturists. Model calibration is often required before practical applications. However, when multiple models and optimization methods are applied for different varieties, it is rarely known which factor tends to mostly affect the calibration results. We mainly aim to investigate the main source of the variability in the modelling errors for the flowering timings of two important varieties of vine in the Douro Demarcated Region (DDR) of Portugal; this is based on five phenology model simulations that use optimal parameters and that are estimated by three optimization algorithms (MLE, SA and SCEUA).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An expanded framing of ecosystem services is needed for a sustainable urban future</title>
      <link>/publication/p20220414_rser/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/p20220414_rser/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     Urban activities are an important driver of ecosystem services decline. Sustainable urbanisation necessitates anticipating and mitigating these negative socio-ecological impacts, both within and beyond city boundaries. There is a lack of scalable, dynamic models of changes to ecosystems wrought by urban processes. We developed a system dynamics model, ESTIMUM, to predict locations, types, and magnitude of changes in ecosystem services. We tested the model in Lisbon (Portugal) under four specific urban development scenarios – a base case scenario and three local sustainability-driven scenarios – to the year 2050.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projections of Climate Change Impacts on Flowering-Veraison Water Deficits for Riesling and Müller-Thurgau in Germany</title>
      <link>/publication/p20220321_remotesensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/p20220321_remotesensing/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     With global warming, grapevine is expected to be increasingly exposed to water deficits occurring at various development stages. In this study, we aimed to investigate the potential impacts of projected climate change on water deficits from the flowering to veraison period for two main white wine cultivars (Riesling and Müller-Thurgau) in Germany. A process-based soil-crop model adapted for grapevine was utilized to simulate the flowering-veraison crop water stress indicator (CWSI) of these two varieties between 1976–2005 (baseline) and 2041–2070 (future period) based on a suite of bias-adjusted regional climate model (RCM) simulations under RCP4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implications of model uncertainty for investment decisions to manage intermittent sewer overflows</title>
      <link>/publication/p20210203_wr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/p20210203_wr/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     Uncertainty in urban drainage modelling studies presents challenges to decision makers with limited investment resources attempting to achieve regulatory compliance for intermittent discharges from Combined Sewer Overflows. This paper presents the development of a new decision-making approach to address two key challenges encountered when attempting to manage sewer overflows, these are (i) the implications of different risk preferences of individuals for investment decisions; and (ii) how to utilize information on uncertainties in system performance predictions due to input or parameter uncertainty while comparing decision alternatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multivariate autoregressive modelling and conditional simulation for temporal uncertainty analysis of an urban watersystem in Luxembourg</title>
      <link>/publication/p20210113_hess/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/p20210113_hess/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     Uncertainty is often ignored in urban water systems modelling. Commercial software used in engineering practice often ignores the uncertainties of input variables and their propagation because of a lack of user-friendly implementations. This can have serious consequences, such as the wrong dimensioning of urban drainage systems (UDSs) and the inaccurate estimation of pollution released to the environment. This paper introduces an uncertainty analysis in urban drainage modelling, built on existing methods and applied to a case study in the Haute-Sûre catchment in Luxembourg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Data-Driven Surrogate Modelling Approach for Acceleration of Short-Term Simulations of a Dynamic Urban Drainage Simulator</title>
      <link>/publication/p20181213_water_surrogate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/p20181213_water_surrogate/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     In this study, applicability of a data-driven Gaussian Process Emulator (GPE) technique to develop a dynamic surrogate model for a computationally expensive urban drainage simulator is investigated. Considering rainfall time series as the main driving force is a challenge in this regard due to the high dimensionality problem. However, this problem can be less relevant when the focus is only on short-term simulations. The novelty of this research is the consideration of short-term rainfall time series as training parameters for the GPE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>stUPscales, an R-Package for Spatio-Temporal Uncertainty Propagation across Multiple Scales with Examples in Urban Water Modelling</title>
      <link>/publication/p20180623_water_stupscales/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/p20180623_water_stupscales/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     Integrated environmental modelling requires coupling sub-models at different spatial and temporal scales, thus accounting for change of support procedures (aggregation and disaggregation). We introduce the R-package spatio-temporal Uncertainty Propagation across multiple scales, stUPscales, which constitutes a contribution to state-of-the-art open source tools that support uncertainty propagation analysis in temporal and spatio-temporal domains. We illustrate the tool with an uncertainty propagation example in environmental modelling, specifically in the urban water domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EmiStatR, a Simplified and Scalable Urban Water Quality Model for Simulation of Combined Sewer Overflows</title>
      <link>/publication/p20180613_water_emistatr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/p20180613_water_emistatr/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     Many complex urban drainage quality models are computationally expensive. Complexity and computing times may become prohibitive when these models are used in a Monte Carlo (MC) uncertainty analysis of long time series, in particular for practitioners. Computationally scalable and fast “surrogate” models may reduce the overall computation time for practical applications in which often large data sets would be needed otherwise. We developed a simplified semi-distributed urban water quality model, EmiStatR, which brings uncertainty and sensitivity analyses of urban drainage water quality models within reach of practitioners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multivariate autoregressive modelling and conditional simulation of precipitation time series for urban water models</title>
      <link>/publication/p2017_ewra/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/p2017_ewra/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     Precipitation is the most active flux and major input of hydrological systems. Precipitation controls hydrological states (soil moisture and groundwater level), and fluxes (runoff, evapotranspiration and groundwater recharge). Hence, precipitation plays a paramount role in urban water systems. It controls the fluxes towards combined sewer tanks and the dilution of chemical and organic compounds in the wastewater. Furthermore, small catchments (i.e., areas of about 20 ha) have a fast response to precipitation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science of Science</title>
      <link>/project/sci_sci/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/sci_sci/</guid>
      <description>“The science of science (SciSci) offers a quantitative understanding of the interactions among scientific agents across diverse geographic and temporal scales: It provides insights into the conditions underlying creativity and the genesis of scientific discovery, with the ultimate goal of developing tools and policies that have the potential to accelerate science.” (Fortunato et al., 2018).
A bibliometric analysis on Science of Science.     Web of Science (WoS) is a key “website which provides subscription-based access to multiple databases that provide comprehensive citation data for many different academic disciplines originally produced by the Institute for Scientific Information and is currently maintained by Clarivate Analytics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI4Copernicus 2023</title>
      <link>/talk/2023_ai_copernicus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2023_ai_copernicus/</guid>
      <description>Earth Observation &amp;amp; Artificial Intelligence solutions for climate change challenges   Earth Observation (EO) and Artificial Intelligence (AI) solutions are playing a crucial role in addressing the challenges posed by climate change. As the global climate crisis intensifies, there is an increasing need for accurate and timely information to understand, monitor, and mitigate the impacts of climate change on our planet. EO and AI technologies, when combined, offer powerful tools to gather, analyze, and interpret vast amounts of data, enabling us to make informed decisions and take effective actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arturo&#39;s CV</title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 15:15:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAPEL</title>
      <link>/project/list_chapel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/list_chapel/</guid>
      <description>CHAPEL has the ambition to provide climate information at impact-relevant spatial and temporal scales for Luxembourg and the Greater Region based on current scientific knowledge.      Innovation     Researchers of the Environmental Research and Innovation (ERIN) department at the Luxembourg Institute of Science of Technology (LIST) will perform long-term climate simulations of past and future conditions at spatial resolutions that allows physical processes (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temporal Uncertainty Propagation Analysis</title>
      <link>/project/wur_phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/wur_phd/</guid>
      <description>A Global Priority     Sustainable urban water management (SUWM) is becoming a global priority due to the impact of urbanisation on natural and urban ecosystems. The global population in 2018 was equivalent to 55 per cent of the world’s population residing in urban areas. By 2050, the global population will reach 9.7 billion, with 68 per cent of the world’s population (i.e., 6.6 billion people) projected to be urban (Fig.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geostatistical simulation of space-time stochastic rainfall fields for uncertainty propagation in rainfall-runoff and urban drainage system modelling</title>
      <link>/talk/2019_spa_stat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019_spa_stat/</guid>
      <description>Towards Spatial Data Science   Since 2011, Professor Alfred Stein and colleagues - in collaboration with Elsevier - have been organizing this series of Spatial Statistics conferences every 2 years. The 5th Spatial Statistics conference is held in Sitges, Spain. The conference focus: Towards Spatial Data Science. Covering a wide conference themes:
  Space-time statistics, e.g. geostatistics, point patterns, estimation methods, large dimensions New spatial data sources, e.g. social media, Google, citizen science, crowd source maps Stochastic geometry, tesselation, point processes, random sets Causal statistical modeling Trajectory/movement modeling Predictive modelling Spatial data quality and uncertainty   Space-Time Stochastic Rainfall Fields for Uncertainty Propagation   On 12 July, I gave a talk on application of space-time stocastic rainfall fields and downscaling for uncertainty propagation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clim4Vitis</title>
      <link>/project/list_clim4vitis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/list_clim4vitis/</guid>
      <description>Clim4Vitis is a three-year Horizon 2020 project funded by the European Union Research and Innovation programme.      A Consortium for Viticulture in Europe     The Clim4Vitis project (Climate change impact mitigation for European viticulture: knowledge transfer for an integrated approach) is specifically focused on the topic of climate change and its potential impacts on European viticulture, giving particular attention to two main lines of research:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EOTSA</title>
      <link>/project/list_eotsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/list_eotsa/</guid>
      <description>Remote Sensing and Earth Observation     With the co-development of 52° North (Germany), the Luxembourg Institute of Science and Technology (LIST) developed the toolbox for the European Space Agency (ESA) according to the needs of the NDVI time series analysis community.
The focus of this project was the implementation of a time series analysis toolbox for remote sensing imagery, specifically for Proba-V data, in R. The mission exploitation platform (MEP) at VITO (Flemish Institute for Technological Research NV, Belgium) derives the data from their Proba-V satellite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merging and calibration of radar rain products for quantification of input uncertainty in urban drainage modelling for the Haute-Sûre catchment in Luxembourg</title>
      <link>/talk/2017_enviroinfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2017_enviroinfo/</guid>
      <description>From Science to Society: The Bridge Provided by Environmental Informatics   The 31st International Conference on Environmental Informatics, EnviroInfo, is held in Luxembourg, hosted by the Luxembourg Institute of Science and Technology (LIST). The conference focus: From Science to Society. The themes:
  Applications of Geographical Information Systems and Disaster Management. Environmental Modelling and Simulation. Energy Informatics and Environmental Informatics. Software Tools and Environmental Databases. Energy Aware Software-Engineering and Development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards an uncertainty propagation framework in urban drainage system modelling</title>
      <link>/talk/2015_udm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2015_udm/</guid>
      <description>Most urban drainage models do not pay attention to uncertainty propagation. In particular, commercial software packages as used in engineering practice typically ignore uncertainties due to lack of user-friendly software implementations and tools. However, uncertainties can be substantial and ignoring these may affect decision making. In particular, end users should be aware of uncertainties so that they can take more robust decisions. Thus, research into uncertainty propagation in urban drainage modelling and development of operational systems that can trace the propagation of uncertainties is needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QUICS</title>
      <link>/project/quics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/quics/</guid>
      <description>QUICS was an EU funded FP7 Marie Curie Initial Training Network (ITN) which ran for 4 years, starting in 2014.      The Ph.D. journey started     Since January 2015 I began my Ph.D. research and made part of the QUICS project. The overall aim of QUICS was to provide high-level training and to research the further implementation of the Water Framework Directive (WFD), improving water quality management by assessing the uncertainty of integrated catchment model water quality predictions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Layout Contributors</title>
      <link>/contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contributors/</guid>
      <description>Thank you to all who have contributed both technical and creative skills to this portfolio:
   Yihui Xie  (for the blogdown package)
  Eric Anderson and the team at Formspree for developing a Hugo theme: https://github.com/formspree/blogophonic-hugo
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
